We'll now discuss the Kalman filter,
现在我们将讨论卡尔曼滤波器
which is used for time series in self-driving cars and even flying cars.
卡尔曼滤波器可以用于无人驾驶汽车和飞行汽车时序中
But first, let's look back at
首先回忆下回归
regression and autoregressive moving averages to see how Kalman filters are different.
和自回归移动平均模型 看看它们与卡尔曼滤波器有何区别
Recall that with autoregressive moving averages,
对于自回归移动平均模型
we must choose the lag number for
我们必须为自回归设定滞后数字
autoregression and also the lag number for moving averages.
并为移动平均设定滞后数字
Our choice of the lag parameters can affect how the model performs.
我们选择的滞后参数会影响到模型的效果
What if, instead of trying to find the best lag parameters,
如果我们不尝试寻找最佳滞后参数
we had a single state that represented all of the relevant information from the past?
而是有一个状态能够代表过去的所有相关信息 会怎样？
In other words, instead of choosing values for P and Q,
也就是说 如果不为 p 和 q 选择值
what if we had a set of variables at T minus 1 to represent the past?
而是在 t-1 有一组变量能够代表过去
I'll give you a hint, Kalman filters.
提示下 即卡尔曼滤波器
Also, you may recall that financial data has
我们知道金融数据
a lot of noise relative to its useful signal information.
除了有用信号信息外还有很多噪点
It's often the case that we want to measure
很多情况下 我们只能通过测量与特定指标相关的其他指标
a specific thing that can only measure something else that's related.
来推测特定的指标值
For example, we may wish to measure oil production levels
例如 我们希望测量石油产量水平
but can only measure oil pipeline flows near the production sites.
但是只能测量油田附近的输油管道流量
So, how do we make predictions when we have noisy indirect measurements?
如果只有非直接有噪测量结果 该如何做出预测？
If you guessed Kalman filters, then you're right.
如果你猜测的是卡尔曼滤波器 那么猜对了
When using Kalman filters,
在使用卡尔曼滤波器时
we can assume that the stock returns properties can be summarized by set of values.
我们可以假定股票收益率属性能够用一组值总结
We call these set of values the state.
将这一组值称为状态
Within the state of the time series,
在时序状态中
there is some hidden property that we can't measure directly.
有一些隐藏属性无法直接测量
We can think of this hidden property as a smooth curve which
可以将这种隐藏属性看做平滑曲线
represents the value of the stock return if there was no noise.
表示没有噪点时的股票收益率值
On the other hand, where we actually measure
但是在实际测量股票收益率时
the stock return includes this hidden state plus noise.
数据会包含这种隐藏状态和噪点
So, what we have to work with is a more jagged curve with some randomness in it.
我们需要处理的是上下起伏的曲线 它具有一定的随机性
The Kalman filter is designed to handle this kind of real life noisy data.
卡尔曼滤波器专门用于处理这种真实的有噪数据
The Kalman filter repeats the following steps in a loop.
卡尔曼滤波器会重复以下步骤
The first step is called the predict step,
第一步称为预测步骤
the second step is called the measurement update step.
第二步称为测量更新步骤
First, the Kalman filter predicts the hidden state
首先 卡尔曼滤波器
or value of the stock return as a probability distribution.
将隐藏状态或股票收益率值预测为概率分布
Next, it takes measurements such as
接下来 它会使用实际股票收益率数据等测量值
the actual stock return data and then updates its belief about the hidden state.
更新对隐藏状态的了解
Note that the Kalman filter stores the relevant information in what's called the state.
注意 卡尔曼滤波器将相关信息存储在状态中
Also notice how the Kalman filter is dynamically
并且每次测量时
updating its underlying model every time it performs a measurement.
它都会动态更新底层模型
The Kalman filter uses both the previous time period's state and
卡尔曼滤波器同时使用上一个时期的状态
the measurement of the latest stock return to predict the next state.
和最新股票收益率的测量值来预测下个状态
So all the relevant prior history of the time series is stored in the T minus 1 state,
所以时序的所有相关历史记录都存在 t-1 状态中
and there's no need to look at the earlier time periods.
不需要查看更早时期的数据